voonik.com 2017-05-05

# Privacy Policy - Voonik

This privacy policy ("Policy") details how Voonik Technologies Private Limited ("Voonik" or "we" or "us" or "our") collects and uses your personal information when you use our mobile application Voonik (interchangeably referred to as "Voonik.com"), including any other service provided by us via any other medium related to Voonik (all these services collectively referred to as the "Services").

By visiting and using Voonik.com, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Policy, so please read this Policy carefully before using our Services.

Voonik.com knows that you care how information about you is used and shared and we appreciate your trust in us to do that carefully and sensibly. We assure you that we are committed to respecting and upholding your privacy, and if you have any questions at the end of this, do feel free to contact us at the coordinates listed below.

 **Personal Information**

Personal information, for the purposes of this Policy, refers to information that can specifically identify an individual customer of ours, such as that customer’s name, address, email address, payment data, telephone number etc. This would also include information about an individual’s activities with regard to the usage of our Services, and demographic information, such as nationality, date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, whenever any such information is linked to the personal information that identifies an individual.

Accordingly, we collect personal information from customers to help us personalise and continually improve their shopping experience at Voonik.com. We use your information to assist sellers in handling orders, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about orders, products, services and promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us, display content such as wish lists and customer reviews and recommend merchandise and services that might be of interest to you. We also use this information to improve our platform, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our Services and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

 **Here are the types of information we gather.**

Information You Provide: we receive and store any information you enter on our website or mobile applications or give us in any other way. You can choose not to provide certain information but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customising future shopping for you, improving our platform, and communicating with you. Automatic Information: we receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many websites, we use "cookies" and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses Voonik.com or advertisements and other content served by or on behalf of Voonik.com on other Web sites. Shopping Behaviour: In order to personalise the product feed we present to you on Voonik we collect information based on your shopping behaviour such as products that you view, add to the wishlist, add to the shopping cart and purchase. We also collect the information that you provide when you take our Style Quiz and answer questions regarding Style Preference, Color you like to wear, apparel that you would never wear and your body shape. This information is only collected when you willingly provide it to us by answering the quiz questions and is used only to customize your product feed. Click here for examples of Information Collected.

Third Parties: We may receive Personal information about you from third parties, such as social media services, commercially available sources and business partners. If you access our Services through a social media service or connect a service on our website or mobile applications to a social media service, the information we collect may include your user name associated with that social media service, any information or content the social media service has the right to share with us, such as your profile picture, email address or friends list, and any information you have made public in connection with that social media service. When you access the Website or mobile applications or otherwise deal with any Voonik entity through social media services or when you connect any Website or mobile applications to social media services, you are authorizing Voonik to collect, store, and use and retain such information and content in accordance with this Policy.

E-mail Communications: to help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from Voonik.com if your computer supports such capabilities. If you do not want to receive e-mail or other mail from us, please click on the Unsubscribe link in the email.

Information from Other Sources: we might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information.

By using or continuing to use the site, you agree to our use of your information (including sensitive personal information) in accordance with this Policy, as may be amended from time to time by Voonik.com in its discretion. You also agree and consent to us collecting, storing, processing, transferring and sharing information (including sensitive personal information) related to you with third parties or service providers for the purposes as set out in this Privacy Notice.

 **Sharing Information with Third Parties:**

Information about our customers is an important part of our business and we are not in the business of selling it to others. Voonik.com shares customer information only as described below with Voonik.com and the subsidiaries which Voonik.com controls and that are either subject to this Privacy Notice or follow practices at least as protective as those described in this Privacy Notice.

Affiliated Businesses We Do Not Control: We work closely with affiliated businesses. In some cases, such as Marketplace sellers, these businesses operate stores at Voonik.com or sell offerings to you at Voonik.com. In other cases, we provide services jointly with or on behalf of these businesses.

Third Party Service Providers: We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), processing credit card payments and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes. Further, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Notice and as permitted by the applicable law.

Compliance with the Law: We may be required to share the personal information with government authorities and agencies for, inter alia, the purposes of verification of identity or for prevention, detection, investigation including cyber incidents, prosecution and punishment of offences. Further, we may release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of Voonik.com, our users or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies, organisations, government or regulatory authorities for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. You agree and consent for Voonik.com to disclose your information, if so required under the applicable law. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in a way that is contrary to the commitments made in this Privacy Notice

When you use the Voonik Software, you may also be using the services of one or more third parties, such as Google, Facebook, MSD, Vizury, AppsFlyer, Acra, WizRocket, CleverTap, YouTubeAndroidPlayer, Konotor, juspay, newrelic, squareup, packetzoom, mixpanel, proguard. Your use of these third party services may be subject to the separate policies, terms of use, and fees of these third parties.

 **Examples of Information Collected**

Information You Give Us:

You provide most such information when you search, buy, post, participate in a contest or questionnaire or communicate with customer service. For example, you provide information when you: search for a product; place an order through Voonik.com or one of our third-party sellers; provide information in Your Account (and you might have more than one if you have used more than one e-mail address when shopping with us) or your 'Your Profile'; communicate with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise; complete a questionnaire or a contest entry form; compile Wish Lists, provide and rate Reviews; and employ other personal notification services and Order Notifications. As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as: your name; address and phone number; credit card information; people to whom purchases have been dispatched (including addresses and phone numbers); content of reviews and e-mails to us; the personal description in your 'Your Profile'; and financial information.

Automatic Information:

Examples of the information we collect and analyse include: the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; e-mail address; password; computer and connection information such as browser type and version; operating system and platform; purchase history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other customers to create features such as Best Sellers; the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our website or mobile applications (including date and time); cookie number; products you viewed or searched for; and any phone number used to call our [.] customer service number. We may also use browser data such as cookies, Flash cookies (also known as Flash Local Shared Objects), or similar data on certain parts of our website or mobile applications for fraud prevention and other purposes. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

Information from Other Sources:

Examples of information we receive from other sources include: updated delivery and address information from our carriers or other third parties, which we use to correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily; account information, purchase information and page-view information from some merchants.

Information You Can Access:

Examples of information you can access easily at Voonik include: up-to-date information regarding recent orders; personal information (including name, e-mail, password, communications and personalisation information); payment settings (including credit-card information); e-mail notification settings (including Alerts, Available to Order notifications, Delivers, Recommended for You and newsletters); recommendations (including prior-order history); Wish Lists and products added to cart only if the products are not sold out.

Cookies:

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognise your browser and to provide features such as Recommended for You, personalised advertisements on other Web sites and storage of items in your Shopping Cart between visits.

App & Device Information:

We collect information about your device to make your experience on our app better and to help us analyse app crashes, debugging device specific issues and for marketing analytics. The device information we collect includes: App Name, App Identifier (package name in case of the Android), App Version, App Locale, App Installed Time, App Updated Time, Mobihelp SDK Version, OS, OS Version, OS Locale, Device Brand, Release Keys, Device Fingerprint, Device ID, Device Manufacturer, Device Version, Referrer, Device OS, Device Info Dump, Device Make, Installer, Device Model, Device SW Build (like the carrier/custom branding of the Android OS where applicable), Current Active Network (as WiFi vs Mobile Network), Mobile Network Type (as GRPS/EDGE/HSPA etc), Mobile Network Operator Name, Mobile Network Country Code, Battery Level, Battery Status (Charging/Discharging), Screen Orientation, Device Storage Space Free/Total in MB (Internal Storage), Device Storage Space Free/Total in MB (SD Card).

We also collect referrer information which tells us the third party that referred you to us and can include utm parameters (UTM parameters are simply tags you add to a URL — when your link is clicked, the tags are sent back to Google Analytics and tracked). We also collect information about the channel through which you installed our app, which provides us insights about our marketing advertisements and partners working with us. For example, if you install our app by clicking on an advertisement on Google's platform, we will get information regarding the partner (being Google in this example) and the advertisement you clicked on which is identified by an alphanumeric.

Securing Information & Retention:

We work to protect the security of your information during purchase of any product on Voonik at the time of online payment by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input in addition to maintaining security of your information.We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing.

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personal information (including sensitive personal information). Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.

If you choose a payment gateway to complete any transaction on Website or mobile applications then Your credit card data may be stored in compliance with industry standards/ recommended data security standard for security of financial information such as the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS).

It is important for you to protect against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when you finish using a shared computer.

Use of Information and Duration:

Voonik will strive to protect the privacy and legal rights of users. Any and all Personal and Sensitive Information (as defined here) you provide to us such as user names, emails, phone number, passwords or any other login information or personal information will be available to us and we have the right to use this information until the you communicate with us and direct us not to use it further.  
You agree that all Personal Information shall be retained till such time required for the Purpose or required under applicable law, whichever is later. Non-Personal Information will be retained indefinitely; if you delete Voonik from your mobile device or delete your account on the Voonik website, we will retain your Personal Information for analytical purposes and recordkeeping integrity, as well as to prevent fraud, enforce our Terms of Use, take actions we deem necessary to protect the integrity of our Service or our users, or take other actions otherwise permitted by law. In addition, if certain information has already been provided to third parties as described in this Privacy Policy, retention of that information will be subject to those third parties' policies.  
If you do not want us to use personal information that we gather to personalise advertisements we display to you or for other purposes, please write to us at support@Voonik.com. (If you do not want to receive Conditions of Use and other legal notices from us, such as this Privacy Notice, those notices will still govern your use of Voonik.com and orders placed with Voonik.com, and it is your responsibility to review them for changes.)

Associated Third Parties:

The Services may contain links to other websites, products or services that we do not own or operate, whether posted by us or a third party users of Voonik. If you choose to visit or use any third-party sites or products or services made available through a link on Voonik, please be aware that this Policy will not apply to your activities or any information you disclose while visiting or using those services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any such third-party sites or any products or services on or through them.

International Visitors:

If you are using our services from outside India, please be aware that your Personal Information may be sent to, stored and processed at our servers and data centers which are located in India. Hence by providing your personal information to us through your use of the Service, you agree to that transfer, storage, and processing in India. Also, we may transfer your data from India to other countries in connection with the operation of the Services. Note that each country has its own privacy and data security laws, which differ significantly from region to region, and hence those applicable to Voonik’s area of operation may not be as stringent as those in your home country

Notices and Revisions:

Our business changes constantly and our Privacy Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also. Accordingly, we will be updating this Policy from time to time, and when such changes xare made we shall indicate the date of updation on the top of this document. Any such changes will be applicable to you provided your continued usage of the Services beyond the date of updation. While we may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, we recommend that you check this Policy from time to time to ensure that you are fully informed of any changes that might affect you.

Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make, however, and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers

Please Contact us for further queries: care@voonik.com

We may disclose to third party services certain personally identifiable information listed below:information you provide us such as name, email, mobile phone numberinformation we collect as you access and use our service, including device information, location and network carrier.This information is shared with third party service providers so that we can:personalize the app for youperform behavioral analytics

By accessing the Website (www.voonik.com) and Apps (Android & iOS), You have agreed to the terms set out in this Policy. This Policy should be at all times read along with the Terms of Use of the Website..
